Hello English learners, welcome back to another sports lesson with us here at EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod，今天我们来上一节体育课。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're going to be talking about a very interesting and very difficult game
今天我们要聊一个非常有趣但也很难玩的游戏，
to play and it's golf.
那就是高尔夫。
So we've got some golf vocabulary for you in this lesson.
所以这节课我们准备了一些高尔夫词汇。
And I think we better actually look at a few vocabulary words in vocabulary preview before
我觉得在开始对话之前，最好先预习几个词汇。
we start with the dialogue.
在开始对话之前。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预习。
On vocabulary preview today we have three words and the first one is aficionado.
今天的词汇预习有三个词，第一个是aficionado。
Aficionado.
Aficionado。
An aficionado.
一个aficionado。
A golf aficionado.
一个高尔夫爱好者。
Alright so this basically is a very fancy word of, it's a very fancy way of saying a
好的，这基本上是一个很高级的词，是一种很高级的说法，
fan.
意思是“粉丝”。
Yes, someone who likes something a lot.
是的，指非常喜欢某样东西的人。
Okay so you are an aficionado.
好的，所以你就是一个aficionado。
I like golf.
我喜欢高尔夫。
Yeah, you can also be a wine aficionado.
是的，你也可以是一个葡萄酒爱好者。
Okay, so it's kind of like a hobby.
好的，所以这有点像一种爱好。
Yeah, you know a lot about it and you like it.
是的，你对此了解很多并且喜欢它。
And now our second word is not anywhere in the dialogue.
现在我们的第二个词在对话中并没有出现。
No, but we're going to use it when we explain some of these words so you need to know it.
没有，但我们在解释一些词时会用到它，所以你需要知道。
Okay, the word is club.
好的，这个词是club。
Club.
Club。
A golf club.
高尔夫球杆。
Okay so a golf club is the tool you use to hit the golf ball.
好的，高尔夫球杆是你用来击打高尔夫球的工具。
Right, so it's a long tube basically that looks like a J kind of.
对，它基本上是一个长管，看起来有点像J形。
Yeah, so and you hit the ball with it.
是的，你用这个来击球。
So that's a golf club.
那就是高尔夫球杆。
And now our third word is golf course.
现在我们的第三个词是golf course。
Golf course.
Golf course。
A golf course.
一个高尔夫球场。
A course.
一个球场。
So this is the area where you play golf.
这是你打高尔夫的区域。
Yeah, it's like the golf field.
是的，就像高尔夫场地。
Exactly.
没错。
Yeah, so it's a very big green area where you play golf.
是的，这是一个很大的绿色区域，你在这里打高尔夫。
So those are the three words we have for vocabulary preview.
这就是我们词汇预习的三个词。
So now we could listen to our dialogue for the first time as we listen to our sports
现在我们可以第一次听对话了，听听我们的体育解说员，
announcers, Rick Fields and Bob Copeland and see what happens on this occasion.
Rick Fields和Bob Copeland，看看这次发生了什么。
Good morning, Golf Aficionados.
早上好，高尔夫爱好者们。
My name is Rick Fields and you guessed it, I'm here with my main man, Bob Copeland.
我是Rick Fields，你猜对了，我和我的好搭档Bob Copeland在一起。
Thank you, Rick.
谢谢你，Rick。
As you can see, ladies and gentlemen, we are here in beautiful Pebble Beach where the top
正如你们所见，女士们先生们，我们现在在美丽的圆石滩，
golfers in the world are vying to win the grand prize of $1 million.
世界顶级高尔夫球手们正在争夺100万美元的大奖。
Whoa, that's a lot of cash.
哇，好多钱啊。
Let's go to the course and see how Tiger Woods is doing.
我们去球场看看Tiger Woods怎么样了。
All right, we're here at the eighth hole.
好的，我们现在在第八洞。
It's par four and has some very difficult hazards which many golfers find difficult
这是一个标准杆四杆洞，有一些非常难的障碍，
to avoid.
很多高尔夫球手都很难避开。
Although, I did see Jack Niclaus hit a hole at one on this very same hole.
不过，我确实看到Jack Nicklaus在这个洞打出了一杆进洞。
Tiger Woods is about to tee off and let's see if he has the same luck as Jack.
Tiger Woods准备开球了，看看他有没有Jack那样的运气。
Tiger is asking his caddy for his driver and he seems to be very nervous.
Tiger正在向他的球童要一号木，他看起来非常紧张。
Oh, no, not a good swing at all.
哦，不，这一挥杆很糟糕。
It's definitely not his day today.
今天绝对不是他的幸运日。
On the seventh hole, he got a bogey and before that, he barely made par.
在第七洞，他打了一个柏忌，之前也勉强保帕。
He will definitely not get a birdie on this shot.
这一杆他肯定打不出小鸟球了。
It seems that his ball has flown somewhere deep into the trees.
看起来他的球飞到了树林深处。
He's having a hard time finding it and even his caddy has climbed a tree to try and spot
他很难找到球，连他的球童都爬上了树想找到它。
it.
找到它。
Oh, no, a bear.
哦，不，有熊。
Run, Tiger, run.
快跑，Tiger，快跑。
Somebody call animal control.
快叫动物控制中心。
So, a pretty exciting ending to that dialogue there.
所以，这个对话的结尾相当刺激。
A bear on the golf course.
高尔夫球场上有熊。
Yeah, I wonder if Tiger is okay.
是啊，不知道Tiger有没有事。
I sure hope so because it would be a huge loss to the world of golf.
我当然希望他没事，因为那对高尔夫界来说会是巨大的损失。
Right.
没错。
So, we did learn a lot about golf because they use some very specific and technical
所以我们确实学到了很多关于高尔夫的知识，因为他们用了一些非常具体和专业的高尔夫词汇。
words for golf.
高尔夫词汇。
So, let's look at these now in Language Takeaway.
现在我们来看看语言要点里的这些词。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right.
好的。
So, the announcers were talking about the game and they're talking about the course
解说员们在谈论比赛，他们在谈论球场，
and they're here on the eighth hole and they said that last time, Jack Nicklaus hit a hole
他们在第八洞，他们说上次Jack Nicklaus打出了一杆进洞。
in one.
一杆进洞。
Hole in one.
A hole in one.
一杆进洞。
Okay, a hole in one.
好的，一杆进洞。
So, this is when you hit the ball once and the ball goes in the hole.
这就是你只打一次球，球就进洞了。
Exactly.
没错。
So, it's something very difficult to do.
这是非常难做到的事情。
Yes.
是的。
Right?
对吧？
A hole in one.
一杆进洞。
I've certainly never made one.
我肯定从来没打出过。
Okay.
好的。
So, sometimes it's also called an ace.
所以，有时这也叫ace。
So, it can be a hole in one or called an ace.
所以可以叫一杆进洞或ace。
Ah, okay.
啊，好的。
Now, for our second word, now once we get to the hole, to the ninth hole or the tenth
现在，第二个词，当我们到了洞，比如第九洞或第十洞，
hole, we have to tee off.
我们要开球。
To tee off.
开球。
Tee off.
So, when you tee off, you begin playing.
当你开球时，你就开始比赛了。
Right.
对。
So, it's the very first instance where you put the little ball on the tee.
这是你第一次把小球放在球座上。
And you hit the ball for the first time.
然后你第一次击球。
Exactly.
没错。
So, to tee off.
所以，开球。
Now, another golf vocabulary, they were talking about a caddy.
另一个高尔夫词汇，他们提到了球童。
Right, a caddy.
对，球童。
A caddy.
球童。
Now, a caddy is a person.
球童是一个人。
Yes, it's the person who carries your golf clubs.
是的，是帮你拿高尔夫球杆的人。
Exactly.
没错。
So, he carries your bag, your golf clubs and basically helps you while you're playing golf.
所以他帮你拿包、高尔夫球杆，基本上在你打高尔夫时帮助你。
Yeah, he tells you which way you should hit the ball and maybe, you know, gives you a
是的，他告诉你应该往哪个方向击球，也许还会给你一杯冷饮，照顾你。
nice cold drink and looks after you.
照顾你。
Very good.
非常好。
So, that's a caddy.
那就是球童。
And now, the caddy, since he has to carry all the golf clubs, Tiger Woods asked him
现在，球童因为要拿所有高尔夫球杆，Tiger Woods向他要了他的
for his driver.
一号木。
A driver.
Driver.
一号木。
A driver.
Now, a driver is a type of golf club.
一号木是一种高尔夫球杆。
Right.
对。
It's not a person.
它不是一个人。
No, no.
不，不。
It's a type of golf club and it's a very big and heavy golf club that is used to tee off.
它是一种高尔夫球杆，非常大且重，用于开球。
So, it's used to hit the ball a very long way.
所以它用来把球打得很远。
Yes.
是的。
That is called the driver.
那叫一号木。
Okay, so, and the next thing they were talking about were some different types of scores
好的，接下来他们谈到了在一个洞上可能得到的几种不同分数。
that you could get on a hole.
分数。
And the first one they mentioned was par.
他们提到的第一个是标准杆。
Okay, so, you can make par.
好的，所以你可以打标准杆。
Okay.
好的。
So, the par of the course can be four.
球场的标准杆可以是四杆。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So, basically, the par is the maximum number of swings or strokes you can make before putting
所以基本上，标准杆是在把球打进洞之前，你可以挥杆或击球的最大次数。
the ball into the hole.
击球次数。
Right.
对。
So, it's like the, right, so, when a hole is par four, you should only hit the ball
所以，当一个洞是标准杆四杆时，你应该只击球四次。
four times.
四次或更少。
Four times or less.
是的。
Yeah.
非常好。
Very good.
现在，如果你没打标准杆，还有一些其他情况。
Now, if you don't make par, there are some options.
你可以打柏忌。
You can make a bogey.
好的，柏忌。
Alright, a bogey.
柏忌。
A bogey.
Now, sometimes the golf course is very difficult.
有时高尔夫球场很难。
Yeah.
是的。
So, instead of putting the ball in the hole, let's say in four turns, you do it in five.
所以，不是四次把球打进洞，而是五次。
Okay, so, it's one over par.
好的，所以比标准杆多一杆。
One over par.
比标准杆多一杆。
So, that's bad.
那很糟糕。
Yeah, that's bad because you get a point.
是的，那很糟糕，因为你得了一分。
So, it's kind of strange because in golf, the more points you have, the worse you are.
这有点奇怪，因为在高尔夫中，分数越高，水平越差。
The worse you are.
水平越差。
Yeah.
是的。
So, that is a bogey.
那就是柏忌。
Now, they also talked about a birdie.
他们还谈到了小鸟球。
Birdie is the opposite if you hit one under par.
小鸟球是相反的，如果你比标准杆少一杆。
So, that's good.
那很好。
Yeah, that's good because you have minus one.
是的，那很好，因为你少了一杆。
One less than par.
比标准杆少一杆。
Alright, so, this is actually a lot of weird, crazy, strange language.
好的，这其实有很多奇怪、疯狂、陌生的语言。
Birdie, bogey, caddy, driver.
小鸟球、柏忌、球童、一号木。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue one more time to help us understand?
我们为什么不把对话再听一遍，帮助我们理解呢？
Good morning, golf aficionados.
早上好，高尔夫爱好者们。
My name is Rick Fields and you guessed it, I'm here with my main man, Bob Copeland.
我是Rick Fields，你猜对了，我和我的好搭档Bob Copeland在一起。
Thank you, Rick.
谢谢你，Rick。
As you can see, ladies and gentlemen, we are here in beautiful Pebble Beach where the top
正如你们所见，女士们先生们，我们现在在美丽的圆石滩，
golfers in the world are vying to win the grand prize of $1 million.
世界顶级高尔夫球手们正在争夺100万美元的大奖。
Whoa, that's a lot of cash.
哇，好多钱啊。
Let's go to the course and see how Tiger Woods is doing.
我们去球场看看Tiger Woods怎么样了。
Alright, we're here at the eighth hole.
好的，我们现在在第八洞。
It's a par four and has some very difficult hazards which many golfers find difficult
这是一个标准杆四杆洞，有一些非常难的障碍，
to avoid.
很多高尔夫球手都很难避开。
Although, I did see Jack Nicklaus hit a hole in one on this very same hole.
不过，我确实看到Jack Nicklaus在这个洞打出了一杆进洞。
Tiger Woods is about to tee off and let's see if he has the same luck as Jack.
Tiger Woods准备开球了，看看他有没有Jack那样的运气。
Tiger is asking his caddy for his driver and he seems to be very nervous.
Tiger正在向他的球童要一号木，他看起来非常紧张。
Oh no, not a good swing at all.
哦不，这一挥杆很糟糕。
It is definitely not his day today.
今天绝对不是他的幸运日。
On the seventh hole, he got a bogey and before that, he barely made par.
在第七洞，他打了一个柏忌，之前也勉强保帕。
He'll definitely not get a birdie on this shot.
这一杆他肯定打不出小鸟球了。
It seems that his ball has flown somewhere deep in the trees.
看起来他的球飞到了树林深处。
He is having a hard time finding it and even his caddy has climbed a tree to try and spot
他很难找到球，连他的球童都爬上了树想找到它。
it.
找到它。
Oh no, a bear.
哦不，有熊。
Run Tiger, run.
快跑Tiger，快跑。
Body call animal control.
快叫动物控制中心。
Alright great, so I think it's clear now what type of rules they have in golf and how it
好的，太好了，所以我想现在很清楚高尔夫有什么规则以及它是怎么运作的，
works so why don't we take a look now at some of the phrases that we heard in the dialogue
所以我们来看看在流利度构建中听到的一些短语。
in Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Fluency Builder.
Okay, well one of the phrases I want to talk about is something that Bob Copeland said.
好的，我想谈的一个短语是Bob Copeland说的。
He said, as you can see ladies and gentlemen, we're here at beautiful Pebble Beach.
他说，正如你们所见，女士们先生们，我们现在在美丽的圆石滩。
Okay, as you can see.
好的，正如你们所见。
As you can see.
正如你们所见。
So this usually goes in the beginning of a sentence.
这通常放在句子的开头。
Yeah, it's a way to say I know you can see this.
是的，这是一种表达我知道你能看到这个的方式。
I'm telling you something you know.
我在告诉你一件你知道的事。
Okay, so maybe I'm showing you my house and I can say, as you can see, our living room
好的，所以也许我在给你看我的房子，我可以说，正如你们所见，我们的客厅
is very spacious.
非常宽敞。
Yes, so this is actually a really helpful phrase.
是的，这其实是一个非常有用的短语。
It can help you sound really native-like so why don't we hear some examples of how it's
它能帮你听起来像母语者一样地道，所以我们为什么不听听一些例子，看看它是怎么用的呢？
used.
用的。
Example one.
例子一。
As you can see, we recently remodeled our entire kitchen.
如你所见，我们最近翻新了整个厨房。
Example two.
例子二。
As you can see here, the damage to the building is very serious.
如你在这里所见，建筑物的损坏非常严重。
Example three.
例子三。
As you can see, the hair stylist made a mistake when cutting my hair.
如你所见，发型师在给我剪头发时犯了个错误。
Alright great, so as you can see.
好的，太好了，所以如你所见。
Now for our second phrase, well Tiger Woods wasn't doing very well and the announcer
现在来看第二个短语，嗯，老虎伍兹当时表现不太好，解说员
said it's not his day.
说他今天不在状态。
It's not his day.
他今天不在状态。
It's not his day today.
Alright, so when it's not your day, you're having a bad time or a bad day.
好的，所以当“不是你的一天”时，你正经历一段糟糕的时光或糟糕的一天。
Right, maybe you're having difficulties or you're having bad luck that day.
对，也许你那天遇到了困难或运气不好。
Yeah, so for example, today I had a headache and I ripped my pants and I spilled coffee
是啊，比如，今天我头疼，裤子撕破了，还把咖啡洒在了
on myself so it really wasn't my day.
自己身上，所以今天真不是我的日子。
Okay, it's not your day today.
好吧，今天不是你的日子。
No.
不是。
Great phrase and also very common and makes you sound very native.
很棒的短语，也很常见，能让你听起来很地道。
That's right.
没错。
Now the last phrase, similar to it's not your day, we also heard that Tiger was having a
现在最后一个短语，类似于“不是你的一天”，我们还听到老虎在经历一段
hard time.
艰难时期。
Okay, to have a hard time.
好的，经历一段艰难时期。
To have a hard time.
经历一段艰难时期。
Now if you have a hard time with something.
如果你在某件事上遇到困难。
You have difficulty with it.
你对此有困难。
Okay, now it's not only related to golf, right?
好的，这不只跟高尔夫有关，对吧？
Of course, you can talk about anything like this.
当然，你可以谈论任何类似的事情。
So I'm having a hard time understanding what this word means.
所以我很难理解这个词的意思。
Okay, or when I was in school, I had a hard time with math.
好的，或者我上学时，数学学得很吃力。
Alright, me too.
好吧，我也是。
So to have a hard time means that you have difficulties with something.
所以“经历一段艰难时期”意味着你在某件事上有困难。
So great phrases, great words.
所以很棒的短语，很棒的词汇。
Let's listen to this dialogue for the last time and then we'll come back and talk a little
让我们最后听一遍这段对话，然后回来再聊一点
bit more about golf.
关于高尔夫的事。
Good morning, Golf Aficionados.
早上好，高尔夫爱好者们。
My name is Rick Fields and you guessed it.
我是里克·菲尔兹，你猜对了。
I'm here with my main man, Bob Copeland.
我和我的好搭档鲍勃·科普兰在一起。
Thank you, Rick.
谢谢你，里克。
As you can see, ladies and gentlemen, we are here in beautiful Pebble Beach where the top
各位女士们先生们，正如你们所见，我们现在身处美丽的圆石滩，这里汇聚了世界顶尖的
golfers in the world are vying to win the grand prize of $1 million.
高尔夫球手，他们正争夺100万美元的大奖。
Whoa, that's a lot of cash.
哇，那可是一大笔钱啊。
Let's go to the course and see how Tiger Woods is doing.
我们去球场看看老虎伍兹的表现如何。
All right, we're here at the eighth hole.
好了，我们现在来到了第八洞。
It's par four and has some very difficult hazards which many golfers find difficult
这是一个标准杆四杆的球洞，有很多非常棘手的障碍，许多高尔夫球手都觉得很难
to avoid.
避开。
Although, I did see Jack Niclaus hit a hole at one on this very same hole.
不过，我确实看到杰克·尼克劳斯在这个洞打出了一杆进洞。
Tiger Woods is about to tee off and let's see if he has the same luck as Jack.
老虎伍兹正准备开球，让我们看看他是否能有杰克那样的运气。
Tiger is asking his caddy for his driver and he seems to be very nervous.
老虎正在向他的球童要一号木，他看起来非常紧张。
Oh no, not a good swing at all.
哦不，这一杆挥得真糟糕。
It's definitely not his day today.
今天绝对不是他的幸运日。
On the seventh hole, he got a bogey and before that he barely made par.
在第七洞，他打出了一个柏忌，在那之前他勉强才保帕。
He will definitely not get a birdie on this shot.
这一杆他肯定打不出小鸟球了。
It seems that his ball has flown somewhere deep into the trees.
看起来他的球飞进了树林深处。
He's having a hard time finding it and even his caddy has climbed a tree to try and spot
他很难找到球，甚至他的球童都爬上了树试图寻找
it.
它。
Oh no, a bear.
哦不，有只熊。
Run, Tiger, run.
快跑，老虎，快跑。
Somebody call animal control.
快叫动物控制中心来。
All right, so Marco, I know that in the Western business world, golf is actually super important
好了，马可，我知道在西方商界，高尔夫其实对你的职业生涯超级重要，对吧？
for your career, isn't it?
是不是这样？
Well, many times when you see in movies or the stereotype is that business is done on
嗯，很多时候你在电影里看到，或者刻板印象中，生意都是在
a golf course.
高尔夫球场上谈成的。
Yeah.
是啊。
And yeah, it is true.
而且，这确实是真的。
But sometimes people will invite you out to a golf course and you'll be playing a game
但有时候人们会邀请你去高尔夫球场，你一边打球，
and talking business and relaxing at the same time.
一边谈生意，同时还能放松。
So maybe you negotiate a deal out on the golf course.
所以你可能在高尔夫球场上谈成一笔交易。
Exactly.
没错。
And of course, if you lose, it's a good thing because then the deal will pull through.
当然，如果你输了，反而是好事，因为这样交易就能谈成。
Okay.
好吧。
Well, actually, I know that it is so important for people who are wanting to do well in business
嗯，实际上，我知道这对那些想在商界有所成就的人来说非常重要，
and many people who don't speak English as their first language take golf English lessons.
很多母语不是英语的人都会上高尔夫英语课。
Right.
对。
So not only golf lessons, like how to play golf, but also in English.
所以不仅仅是高尔夫课，比如怎么打球，而且是用英语来上。
Like how to talk about golf, how to talk to other people and make deals while you're on
比如怎么谈论高尔夫，怎么在高尔夫球场上和别人交谈并达成交易。
the golf course.
达成交易。
Yeah.
是啊。
Because like in many other sports, golf has also its slang and its terms and stuff.
因为就像许多其他运动一样，高尔夫也有自己的俚语和术语之类的东西。
So yeah, it's very interesting and it's one of those cultural things.
所以呢，这非常有趣，是那种文化现象之一。
That's right.
没错。
So if you have any questions or comments about today's lesson, why don't you visit our website
如果你对今天的课程有任何问题或评论，不妨访问我们的网站
at EnglishPod.com.
在 EnglishPod.com。
Right.
对。
We're always there to answer any questions or doubts you might have.
我们随时在那里解答你可能有的任何问题或疑惑。
And until next time, we'll see you there.
下次再见，我们会在那里等你。
Goodbye.
再见。
Well, I guess I neglected to make a decision.
嗯，我想我忘了做决定。